if it's broke. I don't know if you saw
John Arnold, you know, probably greatest
energy trader of all time. Uh he posted
a uh a chart um this week. This is going
to blow your mind if you didn't see
this. He writes nearly three times as
many people, 44% versus 15%. So nearly
three times as many people say they'd
support a nuclear power plant being
built near where they live rather than a
data center. That is insane. And then
somebody else pointed out twice as many
people would support a coal power plant
being built near them compared to a data
center.
I mean, I saw this. I looked 14 times at
the chart to make sure that he read it
correctly. This is like crazy town we're
entering now of the fear, not even of
AI. I mean, yes, there's the fear of AI
and flock cameras and kind of that whole
thing, but we're talking specifically
about a building that you put computers
in that delivers super intelligence for
pennies to people.
I don't even know how to discuss this
anymore when I see data like this.
>> Um, you do uh
so
everything is
>> I don't think I don't think I'm allowed
to say what I think. That's the problem.
Well, let's let's just keep it this way.
I mean,
it's impossible to comprehend how much
information that we take in in our heads
because of the smartphone. Um, and how
easily our brains get programmed based
on the stuff that we read in there and
it becomes a confir confirmation bias
when you only listen to the people that
are sending the things that you want to
read and go through it. So, I don't
think people know how the human brain
works, but if it You've heard what PTSD
is. Um, to get PTSD, if you're
repetitively having a story sent to you,
no matter what, your brain starts to
change and you start saying things or
believing things that don't have to be
true. You just don't have enough
information in your head to think about
the other side. And I'll just give you
my own anecdote without naming people.
But
so, I'm an introvert. I really like to
hang around in my home. um it's hard to
get me out of it. Uh but I do like
intellectual people that provoke thought
and I I I like people that um that
really challenge me. It's one of the
reasons why I spend a lot of time in
podcasts. It's the reason why I spend a
lot of time in YouTube. But if you put
me in a room with someone who's got, you
know, I can have a conversation with
about a lot of different topics and we
can go in and out in and out. But I had
a conversation with someone over the
summertime in Maine where their views
shocked me on this issue. Shocked me.
And I said, I know for a fact that at
least 70% of what you just said to me is
not true. And the reason I know that is
cuz I spend so many hours on data
centers and I wanted to hear whether any
of what you just said is true.
this person I don't want to give their
job away and everything but let's just
say they are very high IQ graduate of
one of the best universities in the
technical universities in the country
and they literally said to me things
about data centers which are not true
including the water side and when I
brought up the fact about
do you drive by golf courses do you see
the sprinklers on every single morning
do you realize that they use more water
than a data center and the old data
centers are different than the new data
centers and things change. Where did you
get your information from? I realize
more and more in life that when I have
conversations with people once I read
this, I realize a lot of it has to do
with their government beliefs. A lot of
it has to do with their rigid brain of
what they follow and in terms of where
they're getting their news from. In this
person's case, their news comes from one
TV station and that's where they get it
all. And so I think we're in an age
where this goes on more than it's
happening. and it worries me. But I
think in the case of AI advancement,
I've actually come to the conclusion
that the good side of this is that if we
have things move too fast, bad things
happen. So in a in a world of different
opinions, regardless of where they're
coming up with their views from,
friction to some degree, when you're
moving this fast, actually might be a
positive because I think it allows human
beings to come to a uh a better
viewpoint of AI in a longer period of
time. while the advancement can't get to
the point where it's a bubble, where
everything's blowing up, where we're
building things without any rules. So,
as much as I don't think we should be
having a lot of regulation and a lot of
rules to slow it down, I do believe that
it's going at a pace which allows it to
be handled more because if not,
exponential is something human beings
can't handle and it might drive people
crazier that way.
>> Jordy, you should have just called me. I
could have told you exactly what was
going on. you were talking to you were
talking to an overeducated dumb person
[laughter] like like there's a lot of
those people out there.
>> I'm sure you've been I'm sure you've
heard from many of them in your Bitcoin
days over the last 15 years.
>> Yes. I I mean look it it is uh uh it is
true but it is also in a weird way um
you can be overeducated and it can be a
huge hurdle to understanding the current
world. And you know the example I've
given a couple of people who uh are are
very close friends of mine who maybe you
know have different views on certain
things or whatever and and I'll kind of
you know Toyota 5 them and say you know
how did you get to that conclusion and
it really will come out of like well in
college I was taught blah blah blah
whatever and I say okay that's great if
something is true today that was not
true before how long do you think it
will take to get into a college te
textbook
2 years 3 years 5 years? you know,
there's some like massive lag. And so,
if you read something in a book 10 years
ago, that really means it's probably a
belief from 15 or 20 years ago and it
was cemented in the book and then, you
know, here we go. And so, I don't know
if uh that's everybody. I I don't think
it is everybody like, you know, that
their views are just dictated by what
they read in college or something. But I
do think that there is uh a very high
correlation between the people who adopt
new technology, the people who are more
entrepreneurial, the people who update
their thinking on a constant basis. It's
like you kind of are uh almost like a
mental athlete and as a mental athlete
what do you have to do if you are
entrepreneurial or you are constantly
adopting new technology you have to be
quick on your feet you have to
constantly be updating your worldview
you have to take in new information you
have to synthesize it you have to always
be asking yourself is this true is this
real is this something that I want to
incorporate into my thought process if
you work like a nineto-ive kind of chill
job and you don't have a lot of the
mental athlete you know requirements
you can operate off of 5 years ago, you
know, uh, kind of mental framework.
Nothing really changes in your
day-to-day life. And so, you're like
quite literally unprepared for the world
that we're in today because you just
don't have the practice or the the kind
of skill set needed to update your world
view every, you know, at at the pace
we're going right now, every month, you
got to update it, right?
>> So, this is [clears throat] an important
thing and I've written a lot about this.
I I uh I spent a lot of time in my life
studying the brain. I I read Freud when
I was very young from a a psychological
basis and a psychiatric basis to
understand
who I was as a person from my
upbringing. Um we most of our brain
consumes the most information from 0 to
4, but we don't remember anything from 0
to 4. So I went into Freud and
eventually into Jung and Skinner and did
a whole bunch of reading on this stuff
to understand it. Then I wanted to
understand the way that it works so I
could understand how to make my brain
work better. Um, there were all
different types of understanding the
reason people think this way and get
caught in this trap. So I'll give people
a little background on on my
relationship with my father. My father
died recently, but he was an atheist. My
mother was a devout Catholic. So I would
sp I would go to church two or three
times a weekend. She sang in the choir.
Um, and my father told me there was no
God. So, you grow up in a house as a
young kid and you're consuming this type
of information. But the advice my father
gave me, which just shows how important
that little example was to keep my brain
open, and I'll summarize what you said
for people with Thomas Bae and with um
Annie Duke as two people to for them to
to spend time with. Uh he told me,
"Nothing you will hear in life is true
except 2 plus 2 is four." Now, that's
obviously simplified. you can go into
into into all things related to science
and get up with facts. But his point was
true. Meaning everything you'll hear
from a human being is someone's opinion.
And [snorts] if you go through life,
then it it immediately makes you in my
case when combined with my ADHD type
brain hate school because why am I
learning this? You're giving me one
person's opinion from a book. I don't
care because I want to read a thousand
people's opinions and then shape my own.
That is the beginning of a basian brain.
That is the beginning of take in new
information, change your views based on
the information you have. And then Annie
Duke, who wrote the book Thinking in
Bets, who I love to death and had a
great conversation with her on this
whole topic. Life is all about thinking
in bets. You're making bets every day of
your life, whether it's the drive you're
taking into work, whether it's the food
you choose for the day. Every single
thing you're doing is thinking in bets.
And they're all investments in in some
future outcome. And so unless you go
through life being open to new
information and changing your views in
bets that it's a constantly uh formula
that keeps changing, I think you're
going to have a really hard time right
now because the world is changing so
rapidly that if you're stuck in your
views, you become an academic in the
past. But this is what the opposite of
my father was. Everyone that did well in
school thought there was an answer to a
question. They thought there was a grade
that would get them a particular
occupation. They thought they'd make a
certain amount of money by a certain
age. that doesn't exist anymore. I can't
remember the name of the book right now.
Um, but Daniel Pink wrote a book in like
2005 or 2006 which was all about the
left, you know, the change from the
world being dominated by people that
were more mathematical and had this
whole formulaic approach and ones that
were more entrepreneurial and more
artistic. And that's what's happening.
And that's why I keep telling people it
is better to learn how to fail right
now. Fail, get back up, build something
new. fail, build something new, fail,
build something new. Then, hey, I want
to get a job at so- and so, and I want
to be at that company for the next 20
years. That that world doesn't exist
anymore. And I think it fits into what
you were saying, which is when you watch
news or you come up with an opinion.
That opinion cannot be in stone and you
can't reinforce it with sourcing people
that are going to go through it. You
have to be open to different parts. And
that's where the basian side gets in and
the Annie Duke. We're getting close to
the holidays. I say this every year. Go
buy Thinking in Bets for your kids. It
is the single best book that they can
read in terms of making sure their mind
is thinking in a world that's
exponential.
>> I love it. You uh tomorrow on Sunday are